笑得很尴尬 手心直冒汗
Awkward smiles and sweaty palms.
我也不指望能在这里见到布拉德.皮特
I'm not expecting brad pitt to walk into st. Theresa's.
只要有个能逗我笑的人 笑容温暖 头发浓密
Just someone who makes me laugh.Has a nice smile.Full head of hair.
知道吗 就像你这样的人 Frekely先生
you know, somenoe like you mr. Franklin.
真遗憾他们要把你火化
It's a shame they're going to cremate you.
有什么需要帮忙么?
can I help you?
Martin!  martin!
我的钱包就在那儿 拿去吧 你要什么都拿走
my purse is right there. go ahead. take whatever you want.
Irene 你叫我?
Irene? You call me?
Irene?
- 你还好么? - 没事
-  how're you doing? - I'm fine.
Fyi...要我说的话 是那些人的错而不是你
fyi... if you ask me,it's more the guys' fault than yours.
House也有责任
and house isn't blameless either.
要不是他挑拨我们的关系
if he hadn't pitted us all against each other- -
是我的错 我的过失
it was my fault. my mistake.
那玩意一直摆在这里?
was that always there?
你好 没问题
hello. sure.
是House
it's house.
早上好 天使们
good morning,angels.
待会儿看到文件 有一件有趣的病例
as you will see from the file, we have quite the interesting case.
你们一定没碰到过看到 死人又变活的病人
not often do you get a patient who sees dead people.
什么文件?
what file?
你说什么? 半小时前我就给Bosley了
what the hell? I gave it to bosley a half hour ago.
没半小时 就10分钟
it was not a half hour. it was ten minutes.
你先复印了急症室记录
and he made copies of the er records first.
少多嘴 加奶油
less lip,more whip.
我之所以接这个病例
I only agreed to take this case
是因为你说会给我加奶油的咖啡
because you said that this mocha frapalicious would have whip on it.
那好 我去问Foreman这个病例
fine. I'll refer the case to foreman.
不行 Mercy医院炒了他 给我
can't. mercy fired him. gimme.
他被炒了?
he got fired?
他顶撞一个正在窝火的家伙 没被弄死算他运气
he disobeyed a superior officer under fire. he's lucky he wasn't executed.
你怎么知道的? 你在跟踪他的消息?
how do you know about it? you keeping tabs on him?
够八卦的
girls talk.
当Bosley就这么进来的时候
when bosley drags his ancient ass in there- -
我来了
I'm here.
24岁的殡装师工作时癫痫大发作
24- year- old funeral cosmetician suffered a grand mal seizure at work.
他怎么变得像Bosley了?
why does he get to be bosley?
你也想扮Bosley? Bosley是个无性使者
you want to be bosley? bosley's like the asexual messenger boy.
病人认为自己晕过去前被尸体强奸
she had a vision of being raped by a cadaver before passing out.
发作症状排除了是精神病
seizure rules out psychiatric illness.
无癫痫史 无脑外伤或吸毒史
no history of epilepsy,head trauma, or drug use.
3季度换了5个天使 可Bosley还在继续干
bosley keeps his job while they replace five angels over three seasons.
可能是颞叶瘤
could be a tumor to the temporal lobe.
可CT扫描是正常的
not with a normal ct scan.
你是说急诊室医生觉得正常
you mean it appeared normal to the doc in the er.
你开始恢复了 Thirteen
way to get right back on that horse,thirteen.
- 那是Amber - 不错啊 女暴君
- that was amber. - nice try,cutthroat bitch.
这是我听到过最差劲的Thirteen式模仿
that was the worst thirteen imitation I've ever heard.
殡仪馆的化妆间充满了有毒化学物质
funeral home prep rooms are filled with toxic chemicals.
那些尸体 明显都已经死了
and cadavers.  everybody in that place obviously died from something.
有个问题 他就是那个不算医生的?
I have a question.  is he the one who's not a doctor?
子弹不会感染 但是会传染 会寄生...
bullets aren't contagious. but infections,parasites- -
你说我们中有人不能算医生 你说那人是冒牌的
you said one of us wasn't a doctor,and you called him a fraud.
他不是医生 继续 Boz
he's not a doctor.  continue,boz.
- 可能是性传染病 - 为什么不炒了他?
-  could be an std - why isn't he fired?
你们闹矛盾了 我得找个洞钻进去
oh,you're breaking up. I'm going into a tunnel.
黑色宗教狂
dark religious nut.
- 你叫我什么? - 抱歉
- what did you call me? - 'm sorry.
这个礼拜你想叫什么?
what do you people want to be called this week?
Cole  cole.
这我可记不住
I'm never gonna remember that.
Bosley和其他有用的人去殡仪馆
take bosley and the other visible minority to the funeral home.
剩下你们这些年轻的白人 世界是你们的
the rest of you young,white people, the world is your oyster.
做个对比的核磁共振 脑电图 血液检查
get an mrI with contrast,eeg,lp,and blood panel.
天使们 要小心
and,angels,be careful.
他虔诚并不代表他就不会踹你一脚
just because he's religious doesn't mean he won't kick your ass.
- 要打赌吗? - 不
- you want to bet? - no.
我要你别这么对他
I want you to stop being such a jerk to him.
一百美元 下的好
$100. smart call.
那家伙是个软蛋 下一个坐火车的就是他
the guy's a wuss. he's gonna be the next one on the train.
定义一下"踹你一脚"
define "kick your ass.
- 任何身体上的对质 - 还是口头上的?
- " any physical confrontation- - or verbal?
定义"口头上"
define verbal.
任何高于... 70分贝
anything over...  70 decibels.
你不能就这么突然对他好了
and you can't start suddenly being nice to him.
你知道这里鼓励什么
you realize what you're encouraging here.
是啊 有人踹了你一脚
yeah,someone kickin' your ass.
里面的地方比我想的要小
the space inside is smaller than I thought.
别担心 Reena 医生会照顾好你的 对吗?
don't worry,reena. the doctors are going to take good care of you,right?
安定剂一旦起效 你就会感觉好些
once the valium kicks in,you'll feel better.
你好了后我们喝点新鲜的热牛奶
and then we'll have some nice,warm milk when you're done.
我宁可要更多安定剂
I'd rather have more valium.
再等一会儿 看看效果如何
let's wait just a bit,see how it goes.
尽量躺着别动
try to lie as still as possible.
我猜时间老人一定是在 某个地方上了锁
I guess father time's a lock for one of the spots.
Thirteen就是把锁
thirteen's a lock.
他没有行医执照 却还在继续干
he doesn't have a medical license and he's still around.
她害死了一个坐轮椅的男人 还有他的狗
she killed a guy in a wheelchair. and his dog.
他不关心我们的资格和创意
he doesn't care about our qualifications or ideas.
就是想找乐子
he just wants to have fun.
而她就是最后的乐子 因为她令人费解
and she's the ultimate fun 'cause he can't figure her out.
- 真是疯狂的游戏 - 那就辞职吧
- this game is insane. - so quit.
就算输了也高兴
happy to lose the competition.
要是写在简历上 辞职总比被炒了好看
if it's gonna be on your resume,it's gotta be better to quit than get fired.
要么辞职 要么少废话
either quit or shut up.
其实 炒了House会合适得多
actually,with house,getting fired might look better.
House医生是个危险的自大狂
dr. house is a dangerous egomaniac.
这也是我离开的原因 我们在行事原则上有分歧
that's why I left. we had different ideas on how to practice.
很高兴听你这么讲 说说Mercy医院的事
glad to hear it. tell me about mercy.
老实说 Schaffer医生并没给我机会
to be honest,I don't think dr. schaffer really gave me a chance.
显然没有 你在那儿才呆了3个礼拜 发生什么了?
obviously not. you were there for three weeks. what happened?
救了一个病人
saved a patient's life.
这好像不是解雇的理由
that's usually not grounds for dismissal.
- 你和她谈过了? - 是的
- have you spoken to her? - yes.
那还为什么问我发生了什么?
then why are you asking me what happened?
你有一份很棒的简历
you have an excellent resume.
我觉得应该由你自己来说 应该说的事
I felt I owed it to you to hear what you had to say.
她跟你说什么了?
what'd she tell you?
你违背了她的指示和医院手续
that you defied her instructions and hospital procedures.
事情就是这样 我也没什么说的了
that's what happened. nothing more I can add to that.
你可以说是你错了
you could tell me that you were wrong.
似乎你应该早点离开House
sounds like you didn't leave house quite soon enough.
尸体是干净的 她的食物也是
cadavers were clean.  so is her food.
都是未加工的有机物
it's all organic unprocessed crap.
那就是尸体防腐剂的问题了
it's gotta be the embalming fluid.
酒精会对人的精神产生作用
ethanol can have psychoactive effects- -
Bosley! 告诉那个在说话的他是个白痴
bosley!  tell whoever's talking that he's an idiot.
Bosley 要么说他是个白痴 或者告诉我是我错了
bosley. either tell him he's an idiot, or tell me why I'm wrong.
你是个白痴
you're an idiot.
你以为急症室没有排除防腐剂时
you actually think that I'd take a patient who had a seizure in a funeral home
我会接下这个病人?
if the er hadn't already ruled out embalming fluid?
我想应该相信...
I thought we weren't supposed to trust- -
白痴 源自古法语
idiot,from the old french, "
"白痴"  意思就是那些 娘娘腔的 脑袋少根筋的摩门教徒
idiote," meaning effeminate,mentally deficient moor.
从停尸房05年以来的文件里 我发现了点东西
I found something in the mortuary's files from '05.
一名被认为死于肺炎的48岁男性
a 48 - year old male's cause of death was listed as pneumonia,
但验尸报告显示的症状与此不符
ibut the symptoms in the autopsy report didn't fit.
精神混乱 记忆缺失 抑郁症
confusion,memory loss,depression.
疯牛病 有意思
mad cow. very cool.
不 她是个素食者 而且只吃有机蔬菜
no,she's a vegetarian and only ate organic vegetables at that.
再说一遍他是白痴
tell him he's an idiot again.
疾病会由脑组织蔓延
the disease can be spread by brain tissue.
非常之有意思 继续
which is very cool. run with it.
因为情况似乎很"有意思"
so because the answer might be "cool,"
你想给一个24岁的女性做脑切片检验?
you want us to do a brain biopsy on a 24-year- old woman?
不 因为情况之有意思
no,because the answer is something cool,i
我要你们给那个48岁的死人做脑切片
want you to do a brain biopsy on a 48- year- old dead guy.
人都已经埋了
the guy's already been buried.
把他挖出来
we dig him up.
没有法院许可我不会去挖尸体
I am not digging up a body without a court order.
别想成是挖尸体
don't think of it as digging up a body.
这是为了不让下一个人也被埋葬
think of it as keeping another one from being buried.
我干不了
I can't do it.
什么时候我们俩再谈谈
we gonna have another one of those ecumenical discussions
到时候让你信服你的信仰有多荒谬?
where I tell you that your beliefs are ridiculous and you totally cave?
我6点钟要回家
I just gotta be home at 6:00.
又是安息日
the sabbath.
上帝工作了6天 然后就说他得休息一会儿
the lord works for six days, then tells the union he needs a rest.
你知道 要是我有权力 至少会休息两天
you know,if I was all - powerful,it'd take at least two days.
今天礼拜四
it's thursday.
那就是孩子了
well,then it must be the kid.
你裤子上沾着麦片粥
you have oatmeal on your pants.
你在那儿安了照相机?
do you have a camera in here?
没有 我猜的
no. I was guessing.
昨天和前天都沾着
he had oatmeal on his pants yesterday and the day before.
叫你妻子照顾孩子
have one of your wives look after the spawn.
我是单身父亲
I'm a single dad.
单身妈妈呢?
where's the single mom?
我不知道
I have no idea.
有意思 你是说判断上的错误
interesting. you claim a lapse of judgment,
还是说判断上的错误 就是信仰上的错误?
or you gonna admit that a lapse in judgment is a lapse in faith?
他走了
he's gone.
合情合理 家最重要
fair enough.  family comes first.
Cuddy医生 我是Amber Volakis House医生的新同事
dr. cuddy,I'm amber volakis,one of dr. house's new fellows.
性骚扰投诉去找人力资源部 压力过大可申请职业补偿
sexual harassment claims go through h. r. stress-related leaves through worker's comp,
任何犯罪指控
and any accusations of criminal activities
直接去找普林斯顿平原市警察局
go directly to the princeton plainsboro police department.
实际上 我是在想诊所今晚是否需要帮忙
actually,I was wondering if you needed any extra help in the clinic tonight.
你这么贴着House不会有进步
you're not going to score any points with house by kissing my ass.
了解 不过我听说House医生 不喜欢诊所义务
understood. but I hear dr. house hates clinic duty.
要是他听了我自愿加班这样的话
if he were to hear through the grapevine that I was willing to work overtime,
帮他减轻点负担...
take some of it off his hands-
我给你的建议是 House叫你今晚干嘛你就干嘛
my advice to you is to do whatever house wants you to do tonight.
至于明晚 你再过来 我会给你额外的任务
and then tomorrow night,you can come back and I will give you extra clinic duty.
这儿的人都有信任问题吗?
does everybody around here have trust issues?
我不知道House要你干什么 也不想知道
I don't know what house wants you to do,and I don't want to know.
但要是你是在干不了 现在就可以辞职
but if you really have a problem with it,quit now.
不然只会变得更糟
it's only gonna get worse.
- 好了 该谁了? - 不是我
- all right,who's up? - not me.
你还没挖过
you haven't done any digging yet.
我是外科医生 要是手出了什么问题 我就完了
I'm a surgeon. if anything happens to these hands,I'm screwed.
让Bosley来吧 只要他还能折衣服...
let bosley do it. as long as he can keep folding laundry- -
有人来了
someone's coming.
我们还不跑?
shouldn't we be running?
是警察的话就跑 要是保安就把他拿下
if it's a cop,run. security guard,I say we take him down.
抱歉我来晚了
sorry I'm late.
- 你到底去哪儿了? - 我迷了路
- where the hell have you been? - oh,I got lost.
我们都到了3个小时了
been here over three hours.
真的迷了路
really lost.
我带了咖啡和甜甜圈
I brought coffee and donuts.
Thirteen 你在这儿长大的?
so thirteen,you grow up around here?
我们是在挖坟 你还想闲聊?
we're digging up a grave,and you want to chit - chat?
我只是找些话说 人们都这样
I'm just making conversation. it's what people do.
你为什么隐瞒一切?
why are you hiding everything?
我问这个问题就是因为 你的确是在隐瞒一切
and I'm asking you that question because you're hiding everything.
我很担心 你肯定有什么问题
there's something seriously wrong with you. I'm worried.
不 你不会
no,you're not.
好吧 但我很恼火 因为我发现你不是个怪人
fine,but I am freaked,because I don't think you're a freak.
我想你是故意这样 因为你知道House会感兴趣
I think you're doing this on purpose because you know house will be intrigued.
是的 我在这儿长大
yeah,I grew up around here.
亲爱的 我回到家了
honey,I'm home.
- 拿铁撬 - 不 下面地方不够大
get the crowbar. no,there's not enough room to maneuver a crowbar down here.
哦 上帝保佑
oh,god help us.
- 什么? - 看到什么了?
- what the hell? - what is it?
是脚 他们埋反了
ankles. they buried the guy the wrong way around.
休息室里都是泥
the doctor's lounge is covered in mud.
餐厅里没果冻了 Thirteen和女暴君有点争执
thirteen and cutthroat bitch had a disagreement, and the cafeteria was out of jell- o.
还有铁镐
there were pickaxes.
不是你叫他们去挖死人了 就是你想造铁路
either you had them dig up a body,or you're building a railroad.
一小块脑子 都没用了
a little tiny piece of his brain. seemed a waste.
他又不需要
he wasn't using it anymore.
这就是你的狡辩?  "我们刚把他肢解了"?
that's your defense? "we just dismembered him"?
他们在查是不是克雅氏病
they're looking for creutzfeldt - jakob.
有结果了吗?
you get the results yet?
你很喜欢我嘴巴里的气味吗?
does my breath smell baited to you?
是啊 要是知道什么了就告诉我
yes. let me know when you hear anything.
顺便把那地方弄干净
and get that mess in the shower area cleaned up.
我认识那人
I know just the guy.
他们多少人同意挖坟?
how many of them agreed to dig up a grave?
六个
six.
但是别担心 没去的那个不是在原则上不同意
but don't worry,the one who didn't didn't stand on principle.
他只是要去给孩子换尿布
he just had a diaper to change.
我真觉得这个团队不会作出错误的选择
I really think there are no bad choices in this group.
你们进来时没把鞋擦干净吗?
you guys don't wipe your feet when you come in the house?
休息室 走吧
doctor's lounge. let's go.
为什么是我?
why me?
我不能叫那个黑炭或者女人去干活 否则会太敏感
I can't ask the black guy or one of the chicks to do it, that would be insensitive.
你又不能叫Bosley去 否则你就像在雇个不算医生的
and you can't ask bosley because that'd look like you only hired the non- doctor
去干不是医生干的活
to do non - doctor stuff.
你在拖时间 但你还是得去 然后还不给你拖把
you keep stalling,you're still gonna clean up,but I won't let you have the mop.
带回来样本的 雅克氏病检验呈阴性
sample came back negative for creutzfeldt - jakob.
这样的讨论不会花多少时间
well,that discussion didn't last long.
我就不知道还会是什么原因 原来的推测...
I just don't know what else there is.  we had an idea.
看来是错的
it was wrong.
好啊 那我们都回家
well,we can go home.
我是说 既然不知道她出了什么问题
I mean,we have no idea what's wrong with her.
就是说有可能根本不是什么大毛病
which means it could be completely benign.
或者 由于我们的轻率 她会因此丧命
or,on the off chance that it's killing her,
我们可以从头再来
we could take it again from the top.
你们已经做了能做的一切
you've already done everything.
我们可能漏掉了什么
we may have missed something.
我就想回家 我确信已经好了
I just want to go home. I'm sure I'm fine now.
Reena 医生最清楚
reena,the doctors know best.
你有些严重的症状 发作时...
you had some serious symptoms. the seizure- -
要是我又发作就来医院 行吗?
if I have another one,I'll come right back,okay?
要是你在开车时发作...
if you have it while you're driving...
你来开车 我没关系
you can drive me. make sure I take it easy.
谁开车?
who can?
我妈妈
my mother.
你妈妈在这儿?
your mother's here?
你说什么呢? 她不就在那儿嘛
what are you talking about? she's right there.
你们检验了所有体液 也看过她的大脑
you sampled every bodily fluid,  peeked in her brain,
侵犯了尸体的隐私
violated a cadaver's privacy,
去挖了尸体
dug up a body,
但还是忽视了一个事实 她还在看到不存在的事物
but missed the fact she was still seeing things that weren't there.4
神经上的病症变糟了
neurological symptoms are getting worse.
要是你们这些天使还是低能儿 知道线索该有多好
it'd be nice if one of you angels/morons had a clue why.
我们都问过了 她从没提过 看到或听到过什么异常事物
we did a full history. she never mentioned seeing or hearing anything unusual.
哦 要是她什么都不说 你怎么知道的?
oh,well,as long as she never said anything. how were you to know?
是脊髓的毛病? 她跟你说没问题?
same thing with the spinal fluid? she tell you that was fine?
实验室的结果都清楚了
the labs were all clear.
那么不是我们走到头了 就是你们漏掉了什么
then either we're about to meet the alpha and omega,or you missed something.
我们忽视了一个新症状
we missed the new symptom.
不是什么新症状 都知道她有幻觉
it's not a new symptom. we always knew she had hallucinations.
看到她妈妈是幻觉
seeing her dead mother's a hallucination.
不知道她已经死了就是错觉
not knowing she's dead is a delusion.
说的有理 你都快成精了
you keep this up,you're gonna have to start wearing sexier clothes.
一氧化碳可能导致错觉
uh,carbon monoxide could also cause delusions.
很多鬼屋...
a lot of haunted houses- -
没有头疼 也没有心跳加速
there's no headache. no tachycardia.
我想是你在医学院没学好吧
I guess they didn't cover that at your medical school.
有没有可能是遗传关系?
what about a hereditary connection?
她现在24岁 她妈妈25岁时死的
she's 24. her mother died when she was 25.
在20年前的乌克兰 有这样的记录就不错了
in ukraine,20 years ago. good luck trying to get those records.
我们要创造新纪录
we start new records.
检验所有符合症状的遗传病例
test for every hereditary disease that fits the symptoms.
至少有40种不同的线粒体异常 另外还有2百多种...
there are at least 40 different mitochondrial disorders,another couple hundred- -
从淀粉样变性开始 一直查到...
start with amyloidosis,keep going until you reach...
"Z淀粉样变性"
zamyloidosis.
你们在检查什么?
now what are you testing for?
或者我该问你们没在查什么?
or should I ask what you're not testing for?
要是能告诉我们你妈妈因何而死 就方便多了
well,we could narrow it down if you could remember what your mother died from.
我妈妈没死
my mother is not dead.
她就坐在那儿
she's sitting right there.
你觉得我们会骗你?
do you think we're lying to you?
让她去吧
leave it alone.
要她相信她妈妈已经死了不会让她好起来 只会使她更痛苦
convincing her that her mother's dead isn't gonna make her better,just miserable.
你也失去妈妈了吗?
you lose your mother?
你觉得我们在骗你吗?
do you think we're trying to trick you?
我们何必这样?
why would we do that?
因为你们很卑鄙
because you're mean.
你们的工作很不称职
and you're not good at your job.
Reena 别这样 你太无礼了
reena,stop. you're being cruel.
他们在浪费时间
they're wasting time- -
尽做些那个坐轮椅的人说的 他们做过的事
doing exactly what the guy in the wheelchair said they'd do.
有个坐轮椅的人在这儿?
a guy in a wheelchair was here?
你们知道我在说谁
you know who I'm talking about.
我被带到这里时他就在转悠了
he's been hanging around ever since they brought me in
抱怨这里的人是多么的不称职
complaining about how incompetent everyone is.
他还说你们杀了他的狗
said you killed his dog.
这样没道理
it doesn't make any sense.
我没兴趣
I'm not interested.
要是你没兴趣就不会来了
if you weren't interested,you wouldn't be here.
我以为只是来吃吃饭
I thought it was social.
不 不是 你总是觉得一切都安排好了
no,you didn't. you always think there's an agenda.
这就是我离开的原因
that's why I left.
你就好在这里
that's why you're good.
- 你需要工作 - 我会找一份的
- you need a job. - I'll find a job.
- 我需要一个能理解House的人 - 让他们慢慢学
- and I need someone that understands house. - they'll learn.
要有一个能控制House的人
I need someone that can control house.
继续找吧 得花点时间
keep looking. might take awhile.
我会把所有人的工资都降低15% 拿出来给你
I'll cut the salary of everyone else on the team 15%,give it to you.
比你另外找工作得到的要好多了
that's more than you'll get anywhere else.
House怎么说的?
what does house say about this?
你是这支队伍里他一直尊重的人
you're the one person on the team that he always respected.
这家餐馆离你住的有20分钟的路 离我住的有半小时的路
this restaurant is 20 minutes out of your way. half an hour out of mine.
你选这里就是要确信House不会突然出现
you picked it to make sure house didn't drop in on us.
这是我的决定 不是他
it's my decision,not his.
那你就去这么跟他说吧 然后自己跑回办公室 我来和他讨价还价
and you tell him that,then run back to your office while I get to deal with him.
我离开是有原因的 这个原因一直都没变
I left for a reason,and that reason hasn't changed.
那么...有什么消息?
so... what's the news?
到目前为止都是阴性的
everything's negative so far.
好的 为什么不全部弄完了再来跟我说?
yes. why wait to finish before reporting to me?
我有事情要做 你知道
I have things to do,you know.
她又看到了别的人
she's seeing someone else.
这又不是什么新闻 都听过了
that's not news. that's olds.
见鬼 上帝为什么要把人设计成这样?
damn it. why did god design the human body this way?
是个坐轮椅的人
a guy in a wheelchair.
这是医院 你是不是有点神经过敏了
in a hospital.  it's enough to give you the heebie- jeebies.
那人有一只狗 她看到的是Stark
he had a dog.  she's seeing stark.
我们上一个病人
our last patient.
如果是Stark 不会去纠缠病人
well,if it's stark,he wouldn't be haunting a patient,
而会去纠缠那个害死他的医生
he'd be haunting the doctor who killed him.
也许她只是无意中听到过别人说...
she probably just overheard someone talking about it- -
也许? 你认为这种情况有可能吗?
probably? you think there's a possibility that the alternative is true?
不
no.
那就别傻了
then go away.
我们是在浪费时间 检验了32支凝胶 还有100支
we're wasting time. we ran 32 gels.
还没搞清楚她妈妈怎么死的...
without knowing how her mother died- -
那就去剩下的100支做完
you're gonna have to run 100 more.
就是说你 一定是那种关心人类生命 以至于不惜花一整天干活的人
and by you,of course, I'm only referring to the people who care enough about human life to put in a full day.
要一起用车吗?
you want to carpool?
要我怎么回应你的问题?
h- how do you expect me to respond to this stuff?
就像这样
exactly like you just did.
我自己有个理论 也许你能证明
I have a theory.  maybe you can help me out.
黑人摩门徒象征了性受虐
black mormon means masochist.
象征了某些特别嗜好
means kinky.
我就觉得有人因为私生子受到了伤害 我说的对吗?
I'm thinking that someone got hurt making the bastard. am I right?
别扯上我儿子
you leave my son out of this.
我没说你儿子伪善 而是在说你
I wasn't referring to your kid's hypocrisy. I was referring to yours.
我们为什么不问问她是怎么死的?
why don't we just ask her how she died,hm?
她不会告诉我们
because she won't tell us.
她觉得她妈妈还活着
she thinks her mother's still alive.
我不是指问病人 而是问她妈妈
I don't mean ask the patient, I mean ask her mother.
有意思
cool.
走吧
come on.
到底什么意思?
what the hell does that mean?
你们俩在说什么语言?
you guys talking your own language now?
很抱歉 下次我弄些视频讲解
I'm sorry. I'll try to include some visual aids next time.
又想怎样?
now what?
我是House医生
I'm dr. house.
你妈妈在这里?
is your mom around?
我为什么要告诉你?
why should I tell you?
你们刚说我不是骗人就是疯了
you're just going to tell me I'm lying or crazy.
不会那样了
not gonna do that.
我真的需要知道她要说的话
I really need to know what she has to say.
你想要什么?
what do you want?
你小时候 她...
when you were young,was she- -
不 没说你 是他
no,not you. him.
那个坐轮椅的男人?
the man in the wheelchair?
不 他很老
no.  he's old.
实际上 他长得像你
actually,looks like you.
没错 这位是House爷爷
yeah,that's grandpa house.
跟他说我会用座机给他回电话
tell him to call back on a land line.
里面信号不好
terrible reception in here.
你妈妈有多痛苦?
how much pain was your mom in?
我是Walter
it's walter.
他说他的名字叫Walter
he says his name is walter.
有什么需要吗?
can I help you?
有位病人在和我的Walt爷爷聊天
my patient's talking to my grandpa walt.
你有个Walt爷爷?
you have a grandpa walt?
没有
no.
所以我怀疑其实她没看见什么灵魂
which is what made me suspect that maybe she's not actually seeing into the afterlife.
你怎么突然对灵魂着迷了?
what is this sudden obsession with the afterlife?
我唯一着迷的是那些 生活在此时此地
only obsession is with the idiots in the right- here-
而又相信有灵魂的白痴
and - now life who think there's an afterlife.
那你要我...
and you want me to- -
没什么 就是来躺会儿
nothing. just need a place to hang low for awhile.
我假装被鬼吓到了
I'm pretending to be spooked.
因为...
because...
因为如果我这个快要脑死亡的病人 觉得我相信她
because if my soon- to- be brain dead patient thinks that I believe her,
也许她会让我和她妈妈的鬼魂聊聊
maybe she'll let me chat with her mother's ghost.
而你觉得是不存在的
the one you don't believe exists.
不错 那鬼魂只是她的幻觉 由一种遗传疾病引发
exactly.  the ghost is a hallucination, which is the result of a delusion,
也就是她四岁的时候  她母亲致死的那种病
of a hereditary disease that her mother died from when the patient was four.
而你觉得可以通过了解她的幻觉
and you think you can tap into her subconscious memory
从而了解她的潜意识
by tapping into her hallucination.
对头
hmm.
也许她不知道她母亲的死因
she might not know what caused her mother's death,
但她总知道母亲死前的行为如何吧?
but she will know how she acted before she died.
你很洋洋自得嘛
you're quite impressed with yourself right now,aren't you?
谁不会呢?
who wouldn't be?
差不多是时候了
well,that should be long enough.
马上回来
back in a flash.
慢慢来
take your time.
我祖父还在吗?
is my grandfather still here?
不在了
no.
他应该马上就回
he should be right back.
他出去买点热奶
he just went to get some warm milk.
但你妈妈还在 对?
but your mom's still here,right?
恩 当然了
yes,of course.
我知道她现在没事 但当你四五岁的时候 她生了病
I know she's fine now,but when you were 4 or 5,she got sick.
没有
no.
肯定吗?
you sure?
她就没有感到任何病痛?
she wasn't in any pain?
我一点也没有
I wasn't in pain.
她只是累了
she was just tired.
有时她会在床上躺一整天
and sometimes she would stay in bed all day.
她有摔倒过吗?
did she ever fall down?
当然了 每个人都偶尔会摔倒
of course. everyone falls down once in awhile.
有时候 不是经常
sometimes. not that often.
多久一次?
how often?
实际上 也许比"偶尔"要多一点点
maybe it was actually more than once in awhile.
还记得在浴室那次吗?
remember that time in the bathroom?
有几次
a few times.
一次她头摔到洗手池上
once she hit her head on the bathroom sink.
血流得一地都是 还沾到我衣服上了
there was blood all over the floor.  I got it on my sweater.
他们带走了她
they took her away.
带她到医院 医生治好了她
to the place where the doctor made her better.
但在那之后 她手脚还利索不?
but before that,what about her arms and legs?
她走路的样子会不会怪? 比如有点驼背?
did she ever walk funny? like sort of bent over?
我以为那是因为从小农活干多了
I thought that was from growing up on the farm.
她的手呢? 会不会用手干活的时候有困难呢?
what about her hands?
没事
no.
不过有时候 我的手会 呃...抖个不停
but sometimes,my hands would,um,shiver.
就像很冷一样 但我不觉得冷 一直都搞不太明白
like I was cold. but I wasn't. I never quite understood.
她的手以前会好像发冷一样的颤抖
she used to get the shivers like she was cold.
给她服用左旋多巴(治疗帕金森病 ) 和溴麦角环肽(抗震颤麻痹)
start her on l - dopa and bromocriptine.
只不过是帕金森而已
it's just parkinson's.
Cole  cole.
你病人状况如何?
how's it going with your patient?
仍然有幻觉
still seeing stuff.
我听说House待你很刻薄
I hear house is treating you like crap.
他对每个人都如此
he treats everyone badly.
恩 但我听说你的情况不大一样
yeah,but I heard you're special.
这个我能搞定
oh,I can handle it.
你不该忍声吞气
maybe you shouldn't.
他会得寸进尺的
he's gonna walk all over you if you let him.
那表明问题不在我而在他
that says nothing about me,just him.
House尊重那些不惧怕他的人
house respects people who aren't afraid of him.
勇敢面对他
get in his face.
必要的时候吼几句
yell if you have to.
我不需要他的尊重
I don't need his respect.
若你想得到这份工 就必须得这样
you do if you want the job.
谢谢你的建议
thanks for the advice.
你别动啊!
you have to hold still!
我在努力了!
I'm trying!
- 该死! 按住她! - 不!
- damn! hold her down! - no!
- 别! - 让我来!
- stop it! - let me do it!
按住她!
hold her down!
不!
no!
Irene  irene.
Irene?  irene?
你刺了我
you stabbed me.
你在发噩梦 不是真的
you were having a nightmare. wasn't real.
我手臂在流血
my arm is bleeding.
不 现在没事了 你的手没有...
no,it's okay now. your arm's not-
帕金森症无法解释她身上的创伤
lesions aren't explained by parkinson's.
还有什么见解吗?
any theories?
被鬼吓得说不出话了?
a ghost got your tongue?
我没事
I'm fine.
脉管炎呢?  核磁共振成像并无检测出脑缺血
what about vasculitis?  mrI didn't indicate any cerebral ischemia.
但她出现了局灶的衰弱麻痹 和尿潴留的症状
but she has shown some focal weakness,urinary retention.
没错 那就是她身上最令人费解的症状了
yes,those are her big mystery symptoms.
脉管炎无法解释为什么出现幻觉
not the hallucinations that vasculitis doesn't explain.
除非是视网膜脉管炎
unless it's retinal vasculitis.
House 这家伙的确聪明  我也肯定他是个适合喝酒谈心的朋友
house,this guy may be smart,and I'm sure he's great to share a beer with.
但如果他连视觉症状是一种电子反应 不关血管事都不知道的话
but if he doesn't know that visual symptoms are an electrical issue,not vascular,two separate systems- -
这可是两个完全独立的系统呢
银行与电力网也一样啊
so are the banks and the power grid.
但如果我不付账 就无电可用
but if I don't pay my bills,my lights go out.
脉管炎限制了血液流向脑神经 干扰了电信号
vasculitis restricts blood flow to nerves,messes with electrical function.
急性间歇性卟啉症更为适合解释这种症状
acute intermittent porphyria's a better fit.
若错诊为卟啉症  其治疗手段会破坏掉病人的肾脏
if you're wrong about porphyria,the treatment could box her kidneys.
用糖皮质激素治疗脉管炎
vasculitis is treated with corticosteriods.
相对来说 副作用会小些
relatively harmless.
- 给她用类固醇 - House 这家伙...
- start her on the steroids. - house,this gu- -
并针对这两种可能病症作检查 免得他又唧唧歪歪
and test for both so he'll stop whining.
大爱之子啊 (HBO 以摩门教生活为主题的电视剧)
big love,have I humiliated you in the last half hour?
我在这半小时里有没侮辱过你?
没有
no.
查收一下你的电邮
check your email.
怎么样?
how's it going?
好极了
great.
他要得到好脸色就得忍受这份痛苦
the only way he could turn any more cheeks is by pulling down his pants.
他可不弱 要撂倒他可得费大力气...
he's not a wuss. it takes a lot more strength- -
喂 我们又不是赌他有多壮
hey,we didn't bet on how strong he was.
所以你想赢这100块钱然后炒了他 就因为他是个信教的人?
so you're gonna collect $100 and fire him because he has principles?
你打算怎样? 很显然你不在乎那100块钱
what's your agenda here? obviously don't care about the $100.
他正派又聪明...
he's a decent,smart- -
你就不管整个团队了
you don't care about the team.
Wilson有没有觉得你很烦? 你喜欢问人问题 又不听人回答
does it annoy wilson when you ask questions and ignore the answers?
当然了
very much.
你只关心我聘了谁 炒了谁
you only care about who I hire and who I fire,
因为你没去看我发你的电邮
'cause you miss going through my mail.
你就是一个劲儿的想控制我
you can't stop controlling me.
没人要控制你
no one controls you.
- 想要回你份工吗? - 不
- want your job back? - no.
真可惜 我也没说要请你
too bad. you can't have it.
她会搞定的
she'll take care of this.
你就等着掏你将要欠我的那100块吧
you can take it out of the $100 you're gonna owe me.
五年前 我在一个会议上遇见了House
I met house at a conference about five years ago.
他可是个人物
he's quite a character.
恩 的确
yes,he is.
也许是我们这代人中 最好的医生了
probably one of the best medical minds of our generation.
同意 从他身上我学到了很多东西
I agree. I learned an awful lot from him.
那当然了
I'll bet you did.
我看到了 在Mercy医院干过一阵子 很好
I see here,just did a stint at mercy. great.
上面写着07年至今
it says here "'07 to present.
你在哪儿待了多久?
" how long were you there?
一个月吧 Schaffer医生很棒  但我们不大合得来
about a month. dr. schaffer was great,but just wasn't the right fit.
等等 那个淋巴瘤病人是你和 Schaffer医生一起治疗的?
wait,was that you with dr. schaffer and the lymphoma patient?
是的 恩 当时情况的确不乐观
it was,um,it was a tough situation.
我本来能做的更好
I probably could've handled it better.
不 Schaffer医生现在该坐立不安了 恭喜你
no. dr. schaffer's got a stick up her rear. good for you.
为什么你那么肯定是淋巴瘤?
what made you so sure it was lymphoma?
在她一份检测报告中 乳酸指数不太正常
there was an unusual lactic acid level in one of her labs.
几个月前我有个类似的病例
I had a similar case a few months ago.
漂亮
beautiful.
天哪 真想有你那份男子汉气概
god,I wish I had your stones.
是啊 有男子汉气概不就出来找工作了么
well,my stones are on the market.
不是这意思 我是说 我希望有你那份男子汉气概
no,I mean,seriously,i wish I had your stones.
这样我就敢把你推荐给管理委员会了
then I could cram you down the board of directors.
但我没有
but I don't.
抱歉 祝好运
I'm sorry,man. good luck.
当人通过视网膜看到东西 它们就会将电信号传送到大脑
when your retina sees something, they send electrical signals to your brain.
这些镜片能接受那些信号
these lenses will pick up those signals.
若信号不正常
if tnals are misfiring,it'll confirm
就说明一个无牌行医的老头都比我们聪明
that an old man without a medical license is smarter than all of us.
你的幻觉就是由...
that your hallucinations were caused by- -
那些不是幻觉 告诉他们 妈妈
they're not hallucinations. tell her,mom.
宝贝 他们是医生
honey,they're doctors.
他们知道自己在做什么
they must know what they're doing.
若他们知道 那个可怜人的狗就不会死了
if they know what they're doing,how'd they kill that poor man's dog?
别这样 你肯定被吓到了
come on,this has got to be freaking you out a little bit.
谢谢你的关心
I appreciate your concern.
没什么好丢脸的
there's nothing to be ashamed of here.
若被你害死的那人的鬼魂没有让你心烦意乱 那你才有问题呢
if the ghost of a man you killed doesn't screw with your head,there's something wrong with your head.
看到了吗? 那个吓着我了
see,that freaks me out.
肯定有人忘在这儿了
someone must've left it in here.
噢 当然了 这说得过去
oh,absolutely. that makes sense.
那只狗在这儿检查眼睛 忘记把它的"项链"戴回去了
the dog was in here getting his eyes checked and forgot to put his jewelry back on.
这没用
this isn't working.
你们只是加重了我的病情  就像他说你们...
you're just making me sicker like he said you- -
怎么了?
what's wrong?
我肚子 好疼
my stomach,it hurts.
眼科出状况了
code in the eye lab.
向前倾 Irene 你得吸气
lean forward,irene. you're gonna aspirate.
不行 好疼
I can't. it hurts.
你们怎么不肯救我?
why won't you help me?
脾脏都化脓裂开了
spleen's ripe to bursting.
你们还以为这是脉管炎?
you guys thought it was vasculitis?
你曾经在House的团队 对吗?
you used to be on house's team,right?
恩
yeah.
这里血太多了 海绵
there's a lot of blood in here. sponge.
- 有什么建议给我没? - 没
- you got any advice for me? - nope.
你得经常忍受他那些废话吗?
did you always put up with his crap?
对
yup.
- 这样忍声吞气对吗? - 不相干
- was it a mistake? - it was irrelevant.
但他开除了你
he fired you.
反正最后无论怎样...他都会炒了你
he'll fire you either way... eventually.
Cameron医生告诉我...
dr. cameron told me- -
- 不 不 不 - 为什么不让我说?
- no,no,no. - why not?
因为...House正在看
'cause... house is watching.
我不是在打比方 往上看
not a metaphor. look up.
你们要继续打屁  还是处理一下那个出血部位?
you guys gonna shoot the breeze or you gonna do something about all that bleeding?
看来出血的不是脾脏 而是肝脏
that's not coming from the spleen. it's the liver.
肝脏坏死了
it's necrotic.
内脏的坏死就快要她的命
she's dying from the inside out.
肿大的脾和坏死的肝 这是典型的急性间歇性卟啉病
enlarged spleen and liver failure are classic a. i. p. it's porphyria and it's moving fast.
这是卟啉症 而且扩散的很快
卟吩胆色素原呈阴性... 读过报告就知道了
pbgs were negative- - if you read the report.
只有在病发时作的卟吩胆色素原测试 才能用于定论
pbg tests are only conclusive if done during an attack,
若你是个真正的医生  就会知道了
which you would know if you were a real doctor.
真是太棒了
that is just great.
什么太棒了我们中哪一个?
- what is? - which one of us is?
你们两个 一起
both of you. together.
热烈的争论 急切地想去证明对方 的观点错误
fighting.  passionate to prove the other one wrong.
完全抛开了病人  但最后能治好就行了
couldn't care less about the patient,but it all works out the same.
我讨厌Thirteen
I hate thirteen.
这不能成为结论
not as productively.
继续
continue.
仍然有可能是脉管疾病
it could still be vascular.
脉管炎已被排除了 类固醇治疗没起作用
vasculitis is off the board. steroid treatment didn't help.
脉管疾病并不只有脉管炎而已
vascular isn't just vasculitis.
一定有什么东西  阻断了肝脏和脾脏的血液供给
something's gotta be cutting off the blood supply to her liver and spleen.
做个内脏血管造影
do a visceral angiogram.
开玩笑的 对吧?
this is a joke,right?
他不可能每次都对
he can't be right every single time.
你肯定在给他灌输你自己的看法 从而让我们难堪
you're feeding him your ideas just to embarrass us.
若我想刁难你  我就会派你去休息室拖地了
if I wanted to embarrass you,I'd have you mop up the doctor's lounge.
天父啊 我恳求你圣灵降临于
heavenly father,I pray thee that thou shalt give the holy ghost
所有信徒们
unto all them that shall believe in their words.
Irene 你在干嘛?
irene. what are you doing?
我要摸
I need to touch it.
Irene 把手放下
irene,put your hand down.
不 给我! 我想要!
no,give it to me! I want it!
给我!
give it to me!
血管造影结果如何?
what'd the angio say?
我们还没做完 她就开始摸我
we couldn't finish. she started groping me.
为了把测试做完 你就不肯牺牲一下 让她上二垒?
you couldn't let her get to second base just to get the test done?
我认为那是三垒了
I think that's third base.
她在抽搐 神志不清 而且唾液分泌过量
she was convulsing,delirious,and hyper - salivating.
我们只好给她打镇定剂
we had to knock her out with lorazepam.
好吧 这肯定不是脉管疾病
well,it's definitely not vascular.
你想我们怎么办?
what do you want us to do?
问题是Joseph Smith会怎么办? (摩门教的创办人)
question is what would joseph smith do?
现在不是时候来...
this isn't the time for- -
驱魔?
casting out the demons?
病人没有着魔 她快死了 要嘲笑我的话 明天随便你
the patient's not possessed.  she's dying. you can mock me tomorrow.
你相信经文中有一切的答案
you believe that the book has all the answers.
只对做人而言 并不关科学事
to morality. not science.
但宗教与科学是两个对立面
but the book is inconsistent with science.
你知不知道多少癫痫病人受人折磨 只因他们以为这是着魔的表现?
you know how many epileptics were tortured because they were possessed?
又有多少女巫被人用石头砸死 只因她们采蘑菇?
how many teenage witches were stoned to death 'cause they took mushrooms?
闭嘴! 我们的病人生命正岌岌可危!
just shut up already! we got a patient dying!
要么开个驱魔处方出来 要么就当我面承认Smith是个好色的骗子
either got to prescribe an exorcism or admit to me that smith was a horny fraud.
我知道她的病因了
I know what she has.
你怎么不早10秒钟说出来?
you couldn't have spoken up ten seconds ago?
你就可以帮我省下这100块钱了
you could have saved me 100 bucks.
蘑菇并不止能让人被石头砸死
mushrooms weren't the only thing that got people stoned to death.
紫曼陀罗 颠茄 曼德拉草根  还有发霉的面包
jimson weed,belladonna,mandrake root,and moldy bread.
是麦角中毒
it's ergot poisoning.
她吃的那种有机黑面包
you'd need damp grain that had been- -
是由完全没加工过的
completely unprocessed and untreated like
受潮的谷物而做成
what's in that organic rye bread she's been eating.
我该走人了吗?
should I be going home?
下班时间到了?
is it 6:00?
所以溴麦角环肽才加重了她的病情 这是一种麦角碱衍生物
it's why she got worse on the bromocriptine- - it's an ergot derivative.
50年内第一次出现这种病例
there hasn't been a case in 50 years.
她一直要喝牛奶  乳制品能中和毒性
she kept asking for milk.  dairy products counteract the effects.
你觉得她知道自己什么病 而且还自己进行治疗?
you think she knew what she had and was treating it?
渴求基于基本需要  这是人进化中所体现的本能而已
cravings based on actual needs. it's a fairly common evolutionary development.
你对进化论没意见吧?
you okay with an answer based on evolution?
没有
yeah.
伪君子
hypocrite.
这是用来做迷幻药用的 但我们的治疗能使你...
it's the stuff they make lsd from. the treatment you're on should- -
所以我一直只是在...兴奋而已?
so I've just been... tripping?
这解释了幻觉 癫痫和妄想
it explains the hallucinations,seizures,delusions.
导致了血管的收缩  也解释了内脏的坏死
constricts the blood vessels, which explains the necrosis.
所以她不存在?
she's not here?
抱歉 是的
I'm sorry. no.
你愿意接受这种解释
the fact that you're even willing to accept that answer
说明药已经生效了
means the medicine is starting to work.
可你会活下去的
but you'll live.
你那么漂亮 Reena
you're beautiful,reena.
你也是 妈妈
you too,mama.
我会想念你的
I'm going to miss you.
妈妈
mama.
如你们所知 你们一共七人 然后...
as you know,there are seven of you and...
我只有六朵玫瑰
only six roses.
那些是牡丹
those are peonies.
但我肯定它们是玫瑰的同类
but I'm sure they're part of the rose family.
实际上 我很奇怪居然还有七个人在这儿
actually,I'm surprised there are seven of you.
你打了你老板 居然还跟没事一样的来了?
you punch your boss and stick around?
把花给我 然后闭嘴
give me the flower and shut up.
别太过火咯
don't overdo it.
我很想将你们全部人留下
now I would love to keep all of you.
但却无能为力
but not enough to do anything about it.
所以据我的仲裁计划  你们其中一人要走人
so according to my arbitrary schedule,one of you has to go.
你开玩笑吧?
you're kidding.
我解出了答案
I came up with the answer.
我挖了坟 我...
I robbed a grave. i- -
在检查室摆了个狗圈 扰乱我思维
planted a dog collar in the procedure room just to screw with my head.
不 我才没...
no,i never- -
你不相信是她做的?
you don't believe she did it?
我当然肯定是她了
I'm sure she did it.
所以我才要给花她 干得漂亮
that's why she's getting the flower. it was beautiful.
虽然有点过分 不过她的确扰乱了你的思维
she just overreached. she got into your head.
没有
no.
她摆了你一道
she owned you.
心理暗示这招不错
planting the idea was good.
火上添油也做的不错
letting it fester was good.
不过放狗圈就愚蠢了
leaving the collar was stupid.
大家都知道 鬼才不会乱摆东西
well known fact,ghosts don't leave things lying around.
那么走人的是我咯?
so am I gone then?
噢天啊 我完全忘记你们两个了
oh,my goodness. I had totally forgotten about you two.
干的不错
well played.
抱歉 Henry
sorry,henry.
我们在一起过得很开心
we had some giggles.
他说的你全部都同意了 你们连说出来的话都一样
you agreed with everything he said. you finished each other's sentences.
所以我才出局了
that's why I gotta go.
你不需要别人来告诉你 已经知道的事情
don't need someone to tell you what you're already thinking.
有趣 我本来也要这么说
funny,I was gonna say that.
- 如果以后你想一起出去玩 - 恩 我知道了
- if you want to hang out - yeah,I know.
给Wilson打电话
um,call wilson.
其他人 明早8点
rest of you,8:00 tomorrow.
给钱就好了
cash will be fine.
估计你对每个男人都这么说
I bet you say that to all the guys.
沾满血泪的金钱 拿去吧
take your blood money.
下次你打算保护谁?
who are you gonna protect next?
要是告诉你了 还会管用吗?
if I told you,it wouldn't work.
我重新考虑了一下
I've rethought some things.
洗耳恭听
glad to hear it.
我打算回来工作 不过有几个条件
I'm prepared to come back on a number of conditions.
我想要你承诺过的加薪 再往上加5个百分点
I want the raise you promised,plus five percent.
我要独立办公室和私人助理
I want my own office and a personal assistant.
也不是不可接受
it's not unreasonable.
我会...一个都不满足你
I will give you...  none of those.
你可以回来 领原来的薪水
you can come back at your original salary.
怎么了?
what's going on?
你根本没重新考虑过 你只不过在别处吃了闭门羹而已
you haven't rethought anything. you've just been blackballed.
你现在是"House简化版"了
you're "house light" now.
只有雇用了"House原版"的人  才会愿意用你这种人
the only administrator that will touch you is the one who hired "house classic.
好消息是 她会假装她不是在帮你
" good news is,she'll pretend she's not doing you a favor.
我周一可以开始上班
I can start monday.